Uh opening statement. First of all,
congrats to Luke Keequley. How about
that? Really amazing and a privilege for
me to be around him, you know, as he's,
you know, covers us on radio, but then
just being around the building
supporting myself, Dan, supporting the
players, always available. Um any really
anybody he can help, you know, sometimes
you'll see him with equipment, doing
things, uh just a class that guy. And um
really cool story. I just my uh last
college football game I was a part of at
USC Emerald Bowl. Luke Keequley was the
inside linebacker for Boston College at
that game. So, it was a pretty cool uh
just to see his career unfold like that.
And then of course uh congrats to T-Mac
uh offensive rookie of the year. What a
tremendous honor, a lot of hard work, a
lot of patience um by the whole group
and really by T-Mac being able to like
grow rapidly as a rookie and uh
assimilate to the professional game. So
really proud of him and the progress and
where he's headed.
>> You guys hired
>> uh No, we can go ahead. You can go
ahead.
>> You guys hired Daryl Bevel. How does
that change up the offense and possibly
yours responsibilities?
>> Yeah, I mean that's that's a great
segue. So um you know Daryl comes in at
a at a really special time. Um this year
going into the season, Bradzick will be
calling plays for the Panthers and uh
this is something that all of us
collectively have talked about as an
organization. it was my idea um to come
up with this and just kind of looking
back and reflecting on it, you know,
thinking about how we've grown this
offense and really wanting to um be able
to advance our football on the offensive
side primarily by letting Brad who's
completely engulfed and entrenched in
what we're doing offensively speaking.
Um his continuity with the system, his
continuity with our players, uh being
able to do that I believe will be the
best thing for us going forward. And um
and for myself, you know, just thinking
about the big picture of it and um the
cultural growth that we've seen happen
over these two years um all across the
board, really on every level of our
building, you know, from strength and
conditioning to athletic training, the
coaching staff development, player
development. Uh this is a great
opportunity for me to be more involved
as each year has gone by. the first
year, as you can imagine, just really
throwing myself fully into the offensive
side of it and um having conversations
with, you know, the different parts of
our team. The second year, starting to
broaden my perspective more to be
involved with special teams and defense
and and now this step allows me to do
that um in a in a greater way uh from a
cultural standpoint. And specifically,
you know, as we're as we're in games,
you know, my ability to be able to
interact with the officials on an
offensive series, you know, where um you
know, in the past two seasons, I got to
go to the next play. You know, there's
another one coming, but uh Brad is
someone I have full confidence in, a
guy, a man that worked together with to
uh to really build what we're doing
here.
>> I'm assuming that's a pretty humbling
decision. Could you take us through the
process of deciding?
You know, my commitment since I've
gotten here has been what's best for the
Panthers, putting our players in best
position to be successful coaches as
well. When I look at this, this allows
me to be in a better position to affect
our team. And this also allows Brad to
affect the offense in a positive way.
He's my primary architect for what we do
offensively with the run game, the pass
game, and the connection of it. And I
saw this as an opportunity to streamline
the work that goes in during the week
and then to have that come alive on game
day for the play caller who has a vision
for what we're doing. And while this is
a shared vision and a shared philosophy
for how we play football, stylistically
speaking, we're not changing any of the
words. Um we're not changing our
approach, but I want all of our
processes to improve and I believe this
is an opportunity to do that.
This was my decision. It was extremely
difficult for me because I do enjoy
calling plays. Um it's a part of the
game that really thrills me. I I get a
lot of um a lot of gratification out of
watching the plan unfold um on Sundays
and and just the high stakes moments.
like those are incredible moments to be
able to make critical calls and to put
guys in positions uh to give ourselves a
chance to win. And so um I certainly
didn't want to give that part up. And
you know, Dan, Brent, myself, Mr. Ter, I
have their full support. This was a plan
that as we thought about it and went
through the process afterwards, I saw
this as an opportunity to make the
Panthers better and um and had a plan
for that. Daryl's a big part of that. uh
bringing his experience from a play
caller standpoint, building our systems,
helping us grow all those things, you
know, and really having that um just
kind of like that that uh having
allowing Brad to have somebody with that
type of experience to lean on, you know,
with my humbling three experiences that
I have. You know, he's lived all of
those, but I want him to to be able to
see more of that. And uh you know,
certainly certainly humbling to have to
kind of swallow that and say, okay, like
am am I the best guy for this job? You
know, that was that was definitely what
I wrestled with, but I believe this is
the right thing for the Panthers.
>> He's as ready as you're going to get.
Yeah. I look back to when I first
started calling plays. Oh, Coach BS is
gone now. He a couple of years ago and
and Coach BS gave me the opportunity.
Asked me, "What makes you think you're
ready?" I said, "I'm just as ready as
I'm gonna get without having actually
done it." And that's how I feel about
Brad. I feel that his his grasp of our
system and our schemes, uh, the mastery
of it, those things and his camaraderie
with knowing who our players are,
knowing Bryce, that's a big piece of
this thing. Um, had a conversation with
Bryce. You know, Bryce is aware of
what's happening and wanted to make sure
that he was a part of this process to to
see the vision of of what I hope uh will
will come.
>> I think it's humility watching him from
afar and then getting to meet him. I
interviewed with with coach Harbaugh in
uh Baltimore right before I took the
Bucks job. I didn't get the job in
Baltimore, but uh spending time with him
in that building to watch how he
impacted everyone and uh they mirrored
his respect, his affection, his
humility, everybody was so
accommodating. It felt like home and it
felt like he was at the head of this
household. And um I got a quick short
story in my time there. We had lunch
together and you know I turn around he's
busting my tray and I'm like coach no no
no no please like I'm going to get
killed for this if people find out but
it was just he was serving you know and
it's that servant that servantthood that
heart of uh being able to just give your
best to th those around you uh that I
really respect and try to emulate in
what I do as well.
>> Yeah.
>> Sean was incredible. Uh, I go back to,
you know, he was our third quarterback
at the time and we went through my job,
you know, was to make sure all of our
quarterbacks were prepared and I call it
the bullpen, but, you know, you don't
get all the throws that the first
quarterback does, but Sean wanted to
make sure he got all the throws and then
he wanted to make sure he put himself in
the most impossible physical positions
to to try to get the throw done. I
learned so much in our times, different
progressions, different types of drills
he forced himself into were things that
I took with me as I continue to coach
quarterbacks over the last couple of
years. But brilliant, asks the right
questions, uh, catches the the the
loopholes um, in protections and
different things like that. A really
sharp guy and and and a great human and
I really enjoyed my time with them.
>> Absolutely. Uh, that was something that
I knew was going to be in his future. It
was just a matter of he was dumb enough
to get into the profession. So, but I
guess he is. So here he is.
They're extremely helpful and the good
that comes out of it. My my connections
with them have been different over the
years. Some guys we hit it off and had
conversations. Other guys there was just
there was some distance there which I
think is help is is healthy. Um but what
they do is they get to spend so much
time with these quarterbacks just
focusing on their technique, focusing on
where their eyes are at. They watch
film. Um, quarterbacks have, you know,
video setups at their homes and
different ways like that where they have
a coach kind of go through these
progressions. So, really valuable and
extremely valuable when you can connect
with them so they understand what you're
trying to get done conceptually so that
there's a little bit of carryover, but
we're not really able to work with them
on that. Um, it just kind of comes up
organically, but um, it's important to
to know what they've been working on.
So, and the most powerful tool as a
coach is what is the player committed
to? Hold them accountable to it. to know
I'm trying to keep my eyes here. I'm
trying to keep my base in this direction
when I release the ball. Different
things like that.
>> What was that like doing? What have you
shared with Brad?
>> I was so nervous uh well beyond the
preseason, but it was it was regular
season one at Minnesota when I was
coaching for the Bucks. And um you know,
I'm just I had my game plan. I knew what
my calls were. felt like I was ready to
go. And I think I think Todd could sense
that I was pretty nervous and he came
over and he just said, "Let it rip." And
gave me the confidence to just call what
trust what I studied, trust what I saw,
and just call the game. He's like, "I
didn't come here to run any type of
offense. Came here for you to make yards
and score points. Let's find a way to do
that." And that was so uh that was so
relieving to me in that
what you most
>> really it's just the work that goes into
it, the grind and trusting the uh
serenity of your office with a cup of
coffee and knowing that those decisions
will be the best for you, especially
when the the moments get intense. Trust
that information. That's what's on your
call sheet versus trying to find some
special play. It's it's not about being
a guru or anything. It's about being a
coordinator and making sure that you
coordinate this whole thing so you can
execute and that's always connected to
what the players can execute.
I think it's a philosoph philosophical
belief. It all starts with what you
believe in, how you're going to score
points, how you're going to be an
explosive offense and how you're going
to set that up. Um, and then from there
it goes to the players. What's best for
our players? We have a giant playbook.
We probably use somewhere between 30 and
40% of what we can actually do. But it's
because our players showed us what we
can do and showed us what we need to
improve upon and see if there's
something we can dust off to to add
value to um to add a wrinkle to. But uh
it all starts with the players,
especially with Bryce and what is Bryce
confident in? What can he do well? What
does he see? And you can see it by his
demeanor, by his back foot, and how
quickly that ball comes out. He's like,
"This is where the decisions are coming
from.
Uh, I would say definitely teaching the
scheme and the decision- making and all
that part of it comes with time and gets
where once you're starting to groove
those different concepts and you have
full understanding, that's when the
mastery piece comes into play. And um,
and that's what we're after in
everything we're doing.
Uh it's been those conversations since
we've been working together and we were
together for a long time in Seattle for
a couple of years and we have a lot of
history back there. But once we got to
Tampa, he was the person I leaned on
because we were installing our offense.
And while I had a vision for what we
were doing, you know, it was Brad right
next to me said, "Okay, how are we going
to implement these things?" Brad helped
me with my interview processes. Um, you
know, it was, you know, at first it was
interviewing at for Vanderbilt, you
know, way back a couple years ago. And
then it was interviewing for the Ravens
and it was interviewing for the Bucks
and he was always a sounding board for
me. So, he's been through this process
with me this whole time and as we've
built offenses and learned our players,
we start to fine-tune what we really
want to do and he's been a part of that
every step of the way.
>> Back in December, you basically said you
couldn't do this without a personal
level to give him.
>> Yeah. really just means the world. It It
allows me to be the head coach and
that's what he's when I was a
coordinator, he allowed me to be a
coordinator by making sure that his
position was right and then also by
really actively being my pass game
coordinator when we were in Tampa. And
so those types of things, the trust
factor that I have for him beyond all
those things, just his work ethic, he's
the hardest working person in our
building and he's there early and he's
there late trying to make things happen.
and it matters to him and and that's the
part that I trust about Brad.
>> We're looking at things. We're looking
at all the things that Daryl uh brought
from Miami and just putting it all on
the table. Part of our our all of us
being here at the combine together, just
meeting during the day is to is to see
we know we have our core that will stay
the same, but what are some of the
things operationally? what are some of
the wrinkles from a schematic standpoint
that we might be able to add uh to bring
value to what we're doing and and
certainly looking at, you know, uh an
offense that I've really respected over
the years and and a and a coaching st a
coaching family with Mike McDaniels,
Kyle Shanahan, and the like that I
really respect and to see like how do
they get to such good football,
explosive plays, all those things.
Wanted to make sure that we're uh
continuing to bring things for our
offense. Where do you see the most?
>> Really just watching him own concepts.
The feedback is really where it's
starting to become powerful. Uh having
conversations with him. We go through
our game plan days, our checkpoints, he
and I talking on the phone, making sure
we have the things that get him excited
and uh that that he feels confident in
executing and and really starting to the
more vocal he gets with what he likes,
what he doesn't like, the closer and
closer we get to a real identity of what
we're doing. And while those things kind
of change with the personnel, with the
players that we have, uh, that's the
mastery that we're after. And the more
he involves himself in what we're doing
there, the more powerful it gets for us.
>> Oh, just continue to grow, be
consistent, show up, and and be a guy
that the guys can count on. And, uh, I
say this all the time about Xavier, but
his work ethic, when I see guys working
hard, that usually works. and watching
him grind, watching him attack it with
everything he has is is why I have
confidence that Xavier will take another
step this year.
>> Uh you feel like you don't have time to
do everything. It will all get done.
>> Personal experience.
>> A couple more. Couple more.
>> Um I really quickly just wanted to uh
talk about coach Capers. So coach Coach
Dom's going to be going to Cleveland to
the Browns. um someone who's had a a
tremendous influence on me, a guy who
started the Panthers and um who has the
ability to walk around the parking lot
and say, "I remember when we planted
these trees and you know, they tower
over us now and cover us," which is a
really symbolic for how he's covered us
as a staff, the development of our
defensive staff. Um Coach Doming us
creates a lot of opportunity for coaches
to step up into new roles. Um, I don't
want to get into the specifics of of
what those roles will be, but these are
guys I learned from coach Dom,
especially with the Gerro, you know,
starting with him, the influence he's
had on him and the rest of the coaching
staff to be able to build our defense up
and uh, these are guys that I really
trust and I'm excited about where we're
going.
>> Yes.
that you
>> uh just watching the care that he has
for what we're doing and understanding
that giving him the pass game
coordinator title comes with
responsibility and expanding his
horizons. He took over third down last
year and was also involved in some of
our play pass things and the general
trajectory is just continue to get eyes
on the whole pass game to make sure he's
got a unique connection with Bryce too.
He was here before we got here and uh
they have they have a really unique
relationship and he un I believe he
understands what Bryce likes, the
different things that he might want to
see, questions he might have and it
really kind of streamlines the
information. So that's a really critical
position for us and a critical role for
for Mike and I was excited to to give
him that promotion.
[music]
>> [music]